let's look at the solution to our
virtual to physical translation speed
quiz we were asked how many cycles do we
need for a load instruction if we use a
three level page table we need one cycle
to compute the virtual address we need
ten cycles to access the outermost page
table 10 cycles flux is the next level
of page table 10 cycles talks is the
innermost page table because neither of
those can be cached plus we need to do
the actual cache access and maybe the
memory so overall we need one plus three
levels of page tables times memory
latency plus one cycle to have a hit in
our cache plus ten percent of the time
we have a miss penalty to access the
memory this ends up being 33 cycles
thirty of which are to access the page
tables